Thomas J. Herzog

thomasJherzog@gmail.com | (408) 476 1944 | San Jose, CA | https://linkedin.com/in/thomasJherzog

Technical Skills

Javascript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, Typescript, Next.js, Apollo, GraphQL, Jest, Node, Express, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Github, Docker, NPM/Yarn, Babel, Webpack, ESLint, PHP

Work Experience

C0d3.com - **Fullstack Software Engineer** - San Jose, CA - Remote Feb 2021 - Present Open source online software engineering education platform built with Typescript, React, SCSS, Next.js, Apollo, GraphQL, PostgreSQL.

- Setup logging / error reporting infrastructure to collect, parse and send alerts correctly from our AWS Lambda serverless hosting environment leading to many bug fixes / SEO improvements.
- Improved web performance reducing user loading time by converting application to a shared static layout and fixed React hydration errors allowing statically generated pages to load quicker.
- Improved user experience by rewriting major existing react components focusing on accessibility.
- Full curriculum review, security audit, documenting issues, and implementing patches.
- Ran Scrum / Sprint planning meetings, and improved code quality through code reviews and testing infrastructure improvements.

Ingoneering - **Software Engineer** - Portland, OR - Remote

Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

Enhanced and maintained a custom-built internal ERP business tool built with vanilla JavaScript, HTML, PHP, CSS, MySQL transitioning to React, Xstate, Docker setup.

- Updated payroll reports to include extra breakdown of weekly reports.
- Reviewed, documented and fixed issues with 'progress complete' feature not updating correctly.

Projects

SPA/PWA - React, Redux, Material UI

https://github.com/tomrule007/orderguide

Responsive single page app prototype built for a regional grocery chain making data more actionable.

Chrome Extension - JavaScript. CSS

https://github.com/tomrule007/highlight-active-row

Five star rated chrome extension with over 50 users built to enhance web page data entry accessibility.

NPM Package - JavaScript

https://www.npmjs.com/package/pdf-template-parse

Cross-browser "PDF parser w/ template engine" to convert pdf documents into organized data objects.

Education

BSc, Electrical Engineering - San Jose State University - San Jose, CA

2008-2011

Dean's Scholar: Spring 2010

About Me

After completing my college senior project, building the <u>SJSU ZEM house (zero-emissions)</u>, I spent one year living and working on a farm studying sustainable farming practices. After which I went on to become sole proprietor of an organic specialty crop farm focused on biological regenerative practices to sequester carbon and reduce greenhouse gases. After 6 years of successfully running the farming business I have shifted my focus towards building technology, understanding its integral role in a sustainable future.